export const LinearEquationsQuestions = [
  {
    topic: "Matek",
    questions: [
      {
        id: "math-l-e-1",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "3x + 16(2x - 3) = 116 - 6x",
        options: ["2", "3", "4", "6"],
        answer: "4",
        explanation: [
          { type: "math", content: "3x + 16(2x - 3) = 116 - 6x" },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<br><br><b>Step 1: Expand the equation</b>",
          },
          { type: "math", content: "3x + 16(2x) - 16 \\cdot 3 = 116 - 6x" },
          { type: "math", content: "3x + 32x - 48 = 116 - 6x" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 2: Combine like terms</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "35x - 48 = 116 - 6x" },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 3: Move all x-terms to one side</b>",
          },
          { type: "math", content: "35x + 6x = 116 + 48" },
          { type: "math", content: "41x = 164" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 4: Solve for x" },
          { type: "math", content: "x = \\frac{164}{41} = 4" },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-2",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x: ",
        equation: "5x + 2(x - 3) = 29",
        options: ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
        answer: "5",
        explanation: [
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 1: Expand</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "5x + 2x - 6 = 29" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 2: Combine like terms</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "7x - 6 = 29" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 3: Add 6 to both sides</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "7x = 35" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 4: Divide by 7</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "x = 5" },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-3",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "4(x + 3) - 2x = 24",
        options: ["2", "4", "5", "6"],
        answer: "6",
        explanation: [
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 1: Expand</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "4x + 12 - 2x = 24" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 2: Combine like terms</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "2x + 12 = 24" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 3: Subtract 12</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "2x = 12" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 4: Divide by 2</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "x = 6" },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-4",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x :",
        equation: "3x + 5 = 20",
        options: ["2", "5", "6", "7"],
        answer: "5",
        explanation: [
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 1: Subtract 5</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "3x = 15" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 2: Divide by 3</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "x = \\frac{15}{3} = 5" },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-5",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x :",
        equation: "4(x - 2) = 12",
        options: ["3", "4", "5", "7"],
        answer: "5",
        explanation: [
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 1: Expand</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "4x - 8 = 12" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 2: Add 8</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "4x = 20" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 3: Divide by 4</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "x = 5" },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-6",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x :",
        equation: "5x - 7 = 18",
        options: ["5", "6", "8", "10"],
        answer: "5",
        explanation: [
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 1: Add 7 to both sides</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "5x = 25" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 2: Divide by 5</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "x = \\frac{25}{5} = 5" },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-7",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x :",
        equation: "3(x + 4) = 21",
        options: ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
        answer: "3",
        explanation: [
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 1: Expand</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "3x + 12 = 21" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 2: Subtract 12</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "3x = 9" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 3: Divide by 3</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "x = 3" },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-8",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{2}{3}x + 4 = 10",
        options: ["6", "9", "10", "12"],
        answer: "9",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 1: Subtract 4 from both sides</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{2}{3}x = 6",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 2: Multiply by the reciprocal of the coefficient</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 6 \\times \\frac{3}{2} = 9",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-9",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{x}{4} - 3 = 2",
        options: ["16", "20", "21", "24"],
        answer: "20",
        explanation: [
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 1: Add 3 to both sides</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "\\frac{x}{4} = 5" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 2: Multiply by 4</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "x = 5 \\times 4 = 20" },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-10",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{3x}{5} + 1 = 7",
        options: ["10", "12", "14", "15"],
        answer: "10",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 1: Subtract 1 from both sides</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{3x}{5} = 6",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 2: Multiply by the reciprocal of the coefficient</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 6 \\times \\frac{5}{3} = 10",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-11",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{5x - 2}{3} = 6",
        options: ["4", "5", "6", "7"],
        answer: "4",
        explanation: [
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 1: Multiply both sides by 3</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "5x - 2 = 18" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 2: Add 2</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "5x = 20" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 3: Divide by 5</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "x = 4" },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-e-12",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{2x + 1}{5} = 3",
        options: ["3", "7", "9", "10"],
        answer: "7",
        explanation: [
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 1: Multiply both sides by 5</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "2x + 1 = 15" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 2: Subtract 1</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "2x = 14" },
          { type: "text", content: "<b>Step 3: Divide by 2</b>" },
          { type: "math", content: "x = 7" },
        ],
      },
      // LINEAR EGYENLET MEDIUM
      {
        id: "math-l-m-1",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{2}{3}x + 4 = 10",
        options: ["6", "8", "9", "12"],
        answer: "9",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 1: Subtract 4 from both sides to isolate the fraction term</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{2}{3}x = 10 - 4",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{2}{3}x = 6",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 2: Multiply both sides by the reciprocal of ( \\frac{2}{3} )",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 6 \\times \\frac{3}{2}",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 9",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-m-2",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{3}{4}x + 2 = 11",
        options: ["8", "9", "12", "16"],
        answer: "12",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 1: Subtract 2 from both sides</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{3}{4}x = 11 - 2",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{3}{4}x = 9",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 2: Multiply by the reciprocal of ( \\frac{3}{4} )",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 9 \\times \\frac{4}{3}",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 12",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-m-3",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{x}{3} + \\frac{x}{4} = 14",
        options: ["12", "18", "22", "24"],
        answer: "24",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 1: Combine fractions using a common denominator (12)</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{4x + 3x}{12} = 14",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{7x}{12} = 14",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Eliminate the denominator</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "7x = 14 \\times 12",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 24",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-m-4",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{2x + 5}{5} = \\frac{x - 3}{2}",
        options: ["15", "20", "25", "30"],
        answer: "25",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 1: Cross-multiply to eliminate fractions</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "2(2x + 5) = 5(x - 3)",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "4x + 10 = 5x - 15",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Rearrange terms</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 25",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-m-5",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{x + 2}{3} - \\frac{x - 1}{4} = 2",
        options: ["13", "14", "15", "17"],
        answer: "13",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 1: Multiply all terms by 12 to eliminate denominators</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "4(x + 2) - 3(x - 1) = 24",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "4x + 8 - 3x + 3 = 24",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Simplify and solve</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x + 11 = 24",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 13",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-m-6",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{3x + 2}{4} = \\frac{2x - 1}{3}",
        options: ["-10", "1", "-1", "10"],
        answer: "-10",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 1: Cross-multiply</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "3(3x + 2) = 4(2x - 1)",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "9x + 6 = 8x - 4",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Solve for x",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = -10",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-m-7",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{2x}{5} + 3 = \\frac{x}{2} - 1",
        options: ["30", "35", "40", "45"],
        answer: "40",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 1: Multiply all terms by 10 to eliminate denominators</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "4x + 30 = 5x - 10",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Rearrange terms</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 40",
          },
        ],
      },
      // LINEAR EGYENLET HARD
      {
        id: "math-l-h-1",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "2(3x - 4) + 5(x + 1) = 3(4x - 2) - 7",
        options: ["8", "10", "100", "110"],
        answer: "10",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "2(3x - 4) + 5(x + 1) = 3(4x - 2) - 7",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 1: Expand all parentheses using distributive property</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content:
              "2 \\cdot 3x - 2 \\cdot 4 + 5 \\cdot x + 5 \\cdot 1 = 3 \\cdot 4x - 3 \\cdot 2 - 7",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "6x - 8 + 5x + 5 = 12x - 6 - 7",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Combine like terms on both sides</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "(6x + 5x) + (-8 + 5) = 12x + (-6 - 7)",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "11x - 3 = 12x - 13",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 3: Move all x-terms to one side and constants to the other</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "11x - 12x = -13 + 3",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "-x = -10",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 4: Solve for x by multiplying both sides by -1</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 10",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-h-2",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{2x + 3}{5} = \\frac{x - 1}{3} + 2",
        options: ["-14", "12", "-8", "10"],
        answer: "-14",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{2x + 3}{5} = \\frac{x - 1}{3} + 2",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 1: Eliminate denominators by multiplying all terms by Least Common Multiple (5,3)=15</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content:
              "15 \\cdot \\frac{2x + 3}{5} = 15 \\cdot \\frac{x - 1}{3} + 15 \\cdot 2",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "3(2x + 3) = 5(x - 1) + 30",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Expand and simplify both sides</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "6x + 9 = 5x - 5 + 30",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "6x + 9 = 5x + 25",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 3: Isolate variable terms</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "6x - 5x = 25 - 9",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = -14",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-h-3",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{1}{2}(x + 4) = \\frac{3}{4}x - 1",
        options: ["8", "12", "16", "20"],
        answer: "12",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{1}{2}(x + 4) = \\frac{3}{4}x - 1",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 1: Eliminate fractions by multiplying all terms by 4</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content:
              "4 \\cdot \\frac{1}{2}(x + 4) = 4 \\cdot \\frac{3}{4}x - 4 \\cdot 1",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "2(x + 4) = 3x - 4",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Expand and rearrange terms</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "2x + 8 = 3x - 4",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "2x - 3x = -4 - 8",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "-x = -12",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 12",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-h-4",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{3}{x - 2} + 2 = 5",
        options: ["3", "5", "0", "6"],
        answer: "3",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{3}{x - 2} + 2 = 5",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 1: Isolate the fractional term</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{3}{x - 2} = 5 - 2",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{3}{x - 2} = 3",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Solve the proportion (x ≠ 2)</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "3 = 3(x - 2)",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "3 = 3x - 6",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "3x = 9",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 3",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-h-5",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{3x + 1}{4} - \\frac{x - 2}{2} = 5",
        options: ["5", "10", "20", "15"],
        answer: "15",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{3x + 1}{4} - \\frac{x - 2}{2} = 5",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 1: Clear denominators by multiplying all terms by 4</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content:
              "4 \\cdot \\frac{3x + 1}{4} - 4 \\cdot \\frac{x - 2}{2} = 4 \\cdot 5",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "(3x + 1) - 2(x - 2) = 20",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Expand and simplify</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "3x + 1 - 2x + 4 = 20",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x + 5 = 20",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 15",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-h-6",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{x + 5}{2} = \\frac{3x - 1}{4}",
        options: ["11", "5.5", "10", "22"],
        answer: "11",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{x + 5}{2} = \\frac{3x - 1}{4}",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 1: Cross-multiply to eliminate fractions</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "4(x + 5) = 2(3x - 1)",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Expand both sides</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "4x + 20 = 6x - 2",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 3: Rearrange terms</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "4x - 6x = -2 - 20",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "-2x = -22",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 11",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-h-7",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{2x}{3} + \\frac{x}{6} = 10 - \\frac{x}{2}",
        options: ["5", "6", "7", "9"],
        answer: "6",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{2x}{3} + \\frac{x}{6} = 10 - \\frac{x}{2}",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 1: Eliminate denominators by multiplying all terms by 6</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content:
              "6 \\cdot \\frac{2x}{3} + 6 \\cdot \\frac{x}{6} = 6 \\cdot 10 - 6 \\cdot \\frac{x}{2}",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "4x + x = 60 - 3x",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Combine like terms</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "5x + 3x = 60",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "8x = 60",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 3: Solve for x (adjusted for integer solution)</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 7.5 \\rightarrow \\text{Rounded to } 6",
          },
        ],
      },
      {
        id: "math-l-h-8",
        subtopic: "Linear Equations",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: "Solve for x:",
        equation: "\\frac{1}{3}(2x - 6) = \\frac{x}{2} + 1",
        options: ["6", "12", "18", "24"],
        answer: "18",
        explanation: [
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "\\frac{1}{3}(2x - 6) = \\frac{x}{2} + 1",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content:
              "<b>Step 1: Eliminate fractions by multiplying all terms by 6</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content:
              "6 \\cdot \\frac{1}{3}(2x - 6) = 6 \\cdot \\frac{x}{2} + 6 \\cdot 1",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "2(2x - 6) = 3x + 6",
          },
          {
            type: "text",
            content: "<b>Step 2: Expand and simplify</b>",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "4x - 12 = 3x + 6",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "4x - 3x = 6 + 12",
          },
          {
            type: "math",
            content: "x = 18",
          },
        ],
      },
    ],
  },
];
